Lumos Maxima.
路摸思
Harry. Harry.
哈利…
Harry, open the door.
去开门
Marge. How lovely to see--
玛姬，好…
Uncle Vernon, I need you to sign this form.
姨丈我想请你帮我签同意着
What is it?
什么同意书?
Nothing. School stuff.
没什么，学校的同意着
Later perhaps, if you behave.
如果你匠话的话，我就帮你签
I will if she does.
我是怕她不让你签
-Oh, you're still here, are you? -Yes.
-吗…你还右在这儿啊 -没错
Don't say yes in that ungrateful way.
不要用这种不屑的口气跟我说话
Damn good of my brother to keep you.
我哥就是太好心才会收留你
He'd have been straight to an orphanage if he’d been dumped on my doorstep.
如果他被丢在我家门口 我一定会把他送到孤儿院
Is that my Dudders? Is that my little neffy-pooh?
我亲爱的小达力在这里啊
Give us a kiss. Come on. Up, up.
来，亲一个
Take Marge’s suitcase upstairs.
还不快把行李拿到楼上去
Okay.
是的
Finish that off for Mommy. Good boy, Rippy-pooh.
攻有妈妈把菜吃完 好乎好乎，杀手卑
-Can I tempt you, Marge? -Just a small one.
-玛姬，要不要来一杯 -一小杯就好了
Excellent nosh, Petunia.
佩妮，人菜烧得好棒
A bit more.
再多一点
Usually just a fry-up for me, what with 12 dogs.
通常我都是… 随便做点东西给自己和狗吃
Just a bit more. That's a boy.
再多一点，这还差不多
You wanna try a little drop of brandy?
你也想吵吵白苦地吗?
A little drop of brandy-brandy windy-wandy for Rippy-pippy-pooh?
只能喝一点点，不要喝醉了
What are you smirking at?
你在偷笑什么 ?
Where did you send the boy, Vernon?
你说你送这小子去哪里读书啊?
St. Brutus’. It’s a fine institution for hopeless cases.
于布缠特 是一所专门收容不良少年的机构
Do they use a cane at St. Brutus’, boy?
那个地方会用藤人条打人吗?
Oh, yeah.
吗，会!
Yeah. I've been beaten loads of times.
我常常被打得好惨唱
Excellent. 1 won't have this namby-pamby...
太好了 我才不相信什么要用过的教育
...wishy-washy nonsense about not beating people who deserve it.
不能体罚来对付学生
You mustn't blame yourself about how this one turned out.
不用因这小子不学好就责怪自己
It’s all to do with blood. Bad blood will out.
这跟血统有关像 先天不良和后天失调嘛
What is it the boy’s father did, Petunia?
这小子的爸爸是做什么的?
Nothing. He didn't work. He was unemployed.
没做什么，他一直没工作 是个无业禾民
-And a drunk too, no doubt? -That’s a lie.
-一定逮柄酒吧 丈们说议
-What did you say? -My dad wasn't a drunk.
-你说什么? -我爸爸没有酌酒
Don't worry. Don't fuss, Petunia. I have a very firm grip.
没事，不要紧张，佩妮 我的手动就是这广强
l think it’s time you went to bed.
我想你应该去睡觉了
Quiet, Vernon. You, clean it up.
六跑，威农 你清乾漳
Actually, it’s nothing to do with the father.
事实上 这跟父亲没关像
It’s all to do with the mother. You see it all the time with dogs.
全因为母亲的血统 看狗就知道了
If something's wrong with the bitch, then something’s wrong with the pup.
要是母狗的血统有问题 生出来的小狗也会出毛病
Shut up! Shut up!
闭中，闭贵…
Right.
干什么?
Let me tell you....
我警告你…
Vernon!
威农
Vernon! Vernon, do something!
威农…快点想办法啊
Stop!
停住
I've got you, Marge. I've got you.
玛姬，我抓住你了
-Hold on, hold on. -Get off.
你不能放手
-Don't you dare! -Sorry.
-你敢放手试试看 ! -对不起
Oh, Vernon.
威农，你还好吗?
Oh, God.
哦，天啊 !
Marge!
现姬
Please!
拜斌
Come back!
快回来
You bring her back! You bring her back now.
你快把她变回来
-You put her right! -No. She deserved what she got.
-现在马上让好恢复原状 -不要，那是她罪有应得
-Keep away from me. -You can't do magic outside school.
-你最好不要来惹我 -你们不能在学校外使用魔法
-Yeah? Try me. -They won't let you back now.
-是吗? 试试看啊 -你会被学校开除的
You've nowhere to go.
然后你哪儿也去不了
I don’t care. Anywhere is better than here.
我才不在乎，哪里都比这里好
“Welcome to the Knight Bus...
炊迎搭乘骑士公车
emergency transport for the stranded witch or wizard.
这是为陷入困境的巫师 提供的紧急交通工具
My name is Stan Shunpike, and I will be your conductor for this evening.”
我的名字叫做史坦桑派 今天晚上我担任车掌，为你服务
What you doing down there?
你为什么要坐地上啊?
-I fell over. -What you fell over for?
-跌倒了 -你没事干嘛跌倒呀?
-I didn’t do it on purpose. -Well, come on, then.
-我又不是故意跌倒的 -好了，上车吧
Let’s not wait for the grass to grow.
哪有那庆多时间跟你罕蘑站
-What you looking at? -Nothing.
-你在看什么呀? -没什么
Well, come on, then. In.
好了，快上车，来
No, no, no. I'll get this. You get in.
我来提行李，你快上于
Come on.
好了
Come on. Move on, move on.
往前走，往前走…
-Take her away, Ern. -Yeah, take it away, Ernie.
-天车唆，琐尼 -好耶，开车唾，琐尼
It’s going to be a bumpy ride.
接下来的旅程很不平静哩
-What did you say your name was? -I didn't.
-你刚刚说你叫什么 ? -我没说啊
-Whereabouts are you headed? -The Leaky Cauldron. That's in London.
-请问你目的地在哪里? -破答酒吧，在伦敦
You hear that? "The Leaky Cauldron. That's in London.”
隐见了吧，责尼? 破签酒吧，在伦敦哩
The Leaky Cauldron. If you have pea soup...
在破俭酒吧 如果那里有豆子汤要超快喝光
...make sure you eat it before it eats you.
免得豆子混把你吃掉
-But the Muggles. Can't they see us? -Muggles?
-太瓜…不会看到我们吗? -县瓜?
They don't see nothing, do they?
他们根本什笨都不会注意到
No, but if you jab them with a fork, they feel.
不过拿又子规他们 他们还是会痛的
Ernie, little old lady at 12 o'clock!
尔尼，十二点方向有个老太太
Ten, nine, eight...
十，九，和八…
.. seven, six, five...
七，六，五，四:……
..-four, three, three and a half...
三，二又二分之一…
...two, one and three quarters.
二，一又四分之三…，
Yes!
生啊 !
Who is that?
他是谁呵?
That man.
那个人
Who is--?
你说他呀，他就是…
That is Sirius Black, that is.
天狼星布莱克
Don't tell me you've never been hearing of Sirius Black.
别告诉我… 你从没匠过天狼星布莱克
He’s a murderer.
他是一个网手
Got himself locked up in Azkaban for it.
因为亲人被关在阿兹卡班
He’s the first one that done it.
他是第一个辽逃成功的犯人
He was a big supporter of...
他是最支持那个人
...-You-Know-Who.
那个人是谁…
l reckon you've heard of him.
你应该区过吧
Yeah.
是的
Him I've heard of.
我是册过
Ernie, two double-deckers at 12 o'clock.
十二点方向有两地双层巴士
They're getting closer, Ernie.
越来越近了“，矢尼
Ernie, they're right on top of us!
要撞上来了
Mind your head.
小心你的头
Hey, guys? Guys?
各位，各位?
Why the long faces?
干嘛把脸拉那庆长?
Yeah, yeah. Nearly there. Nearly there.
好耶，好耶，差不多了…
-The Leaky Cauldron. -Next stop, Knockturn Alley.
-破俭酒吧到了 -下一站，夜行埠
Mr. Potter, at last.
波特先生，你终於到了
-Take it away, Ern. -Yeah, take it away, Ernie!
-天车唆，琐尼
Room 11.
十一号羽
Hedwig.
味美
Right smart bird you got there, Mr. Potter.
隐明的猎头魔自己找来了
He arrived here just five minutes before yourself.
怨也是五分镍前才刚到而已
As Minister for Magic, it is my duty to inform you, Mr. Potter...
身为魔法部长，我有义务告诉你
.. earlier this evening your uncle’s sister was located...
今晚稍早… 我们在南英格兰找到你的姑杂
..a little south of Sheffield, circling a chimney stack.
当时她正统著灯国转围起
The Accidental Magic Reversal Department was dispatched immediately.
魔法意外舌正部派人过去不理了
She has been properly punctured and her memory modified.
他们把你姑妈的氛放光了 也修正她的记居
She will have no recollection of the incident whatsoever.
她会完全不记得… 这整件事情是怎么发生的
So that’s that...
所以…
..and no harm done.
事情解决了 没有造成任何的伤害
Pea soup?
喝豆子汤吧?
No, thank you.
不了，谢谢
-Minister? -Yes?
-部长? -什么事?
-[ don’t understand. -Understand?
我有点不懂 我违反了规则
I broke the law. Underage wizards can't use magic at home.
未成年巫师不能在家里施魔法
Come now. The Ministry doesn't send people to Azkaban...
魔法部不会因为有人把姑妈…
...for blowing up their aunts.
吹成汽球，就把他关到阿兹卡班
On the other hand, running away like that, given the state of things...
可是做了这年事就随便逃家 尤其是在目前的情势下…
...Was very, very irresponsible.
可是非常非常不负责任的哩
-"The state of things,” sir? -We have a killer on the loose.
-请问什么样的情势啊? -现在外头有逃犯啊
Sirius Black, you mean?
天狼星布莱克吗?
But what's he got to do with me?
可是这跟我有什么关父?
Nothing, of course. You're safe. And that's what matters.
当然没关像 你现在很安全，这才是最重要的
And tomorrow you'll be on your way back to Hogwarts.
明天你就可以回埠格桂兹去了
These are your new schoolbooks. I took the liberty...
那冰都是你这学期的教科书
..of having them brought here. Now Tom will show you to your room.
我要书店把你的书都送过来了 现在汤姆带你到客房去
Hedwig.
味美
Oh, by the way, Harry. Whilst you're here, it would be best if you didn't...
对了，哈利，你在这个时候呢 最好是不要到处…
...-wander.
乱逛
Right! You gonna move that bus or what?
喂!到底你要不要移车啊?
Housekeeping.
整理客房
I'll come back later.
我等一下再来
I'm warning you, Hermione.
妙对，我警告你
Keep that beast away from Scabbers, or I'll turn it into a tea cozy.
叫你那焦讨厥的怪物郊斑斑下点 不然我就把怨释成杯起
It's a cat, Ronald. What do you expect?
凶只是焦玫
-It’s in his nature. -A cat? Is that what they told you?
-玫抓老鼠是天生的 -什么猫，我说季是怪物
-Looks like a pig with hair. -That’s rich...
-和拖根本就是一头长毛猪 -真好笑
..coming from the owner of that smelly old shoe brush.
自己状了一焦毛得昔的臭鞋刷
Crookshanks, just ignore the mean little boy.
没关你，牌腿 不要理这个讨屡撮
Harry.
哈利!
-Egypt. What's it like? -Brilliant. Loads of old stuff...
-你去埃及 ? 那里是什么样子? -证呆了，有好多十贵
.. like mummies, tombs, even Scabbers enjoyed himself.
木万伊、金字塔… 连斑斑都玩得很开心
-Egyptians used to worship cats. -Along with the dung beetle.
埃及人以前还会拜猫 是喔，他们还拜绕晴曙
-Not flashing that clipping again? -l haven't shown anyone.
-又拿剪报出来现了 -我才没有拿给别人看
No, not a soul. Not unless you count Tom.
真的没有，除了拿给汤姆
-The day maid. -Night maid.
白天的服务生…晚上的服务生
-Cook. -The bloke who fixed the toilet.
府师…修高所的水电工
-Harry. -Mrs. Weasley.
-还有比利时的巫师 -本斯理太太
-Good to see you, dear. -Good to see you.
-看到你真是太开心了，亲芝的 -我也是
-Got everything? -Yes.
-东西都准备好了吗? -好了
-Yes? All your books? -It’s all upstairs.
-那教科书都买好了吗? -是呀，在楼上
-Your clothes? -Everything.
-所有的制服呢? -全部都在楼上
-Good boy. -Thank you.
-真是个好孩子 -谢谢
-Harry Potter. -Mr. Weasley.
-哈利波特 -本斯理先生
-Harry, wonder if ! might have a word? -Yeah, sure.
-哈利，我可以跟你说身话吗? -当然可以啊
-Hermione. -Good morning, Mr. Weasley.
-妙时 -早安，本斯理先生
-Looking forward to a new term? -Yeah. It should be great.
-等不及要去学校了? -这学期一定很棒
Harry, some within the Ministry would strongly discourage me...
魔法部有很多人… 都强烈反对我告诉你
...from divulging what I’m about to reveal to you.
我现在要说的这件事
But I think that you need to know the facts.
不过我认为必须让你知道实情
You are in danger.
你现在很危险
Grave danger.
非常的危险
Has this anything to do with Sirius Black, sir?
这跟天狼星布莱克有关休吗?
What do you know about Sirius Black, Harry?
你对天狼星的事情了解多少?
-Only that he’s escaped from Azkaban. -Do you know why?
-我只知道他从阿兹卡班逃狱 -知道为什么吗?
Thirteen years ago, when you stopped....
十三年前，当你阻止了…
-Voldemort. -Don't say his name.
-佛地魔 -不要说出他的名字
Sorry.
对不起
When you stopped You-Know-Who...
当你阻止了… 你知道的那个人
...Black lost everything.
天狼星就失去了一切
But to this day, he still remains a faithful servant.
但是一直到今天，他都还半 你知道的那个人，非常地患心
And in his mind...
在他心里
...you are the only thing that stands in the way...
你也是唯一有能力 能金阻止…
...0f You-Know-Who returning to power.
你知道的那个人 恢复力量
And that is why...
这就是为什么
...he has escaped from Azkaban.
他要和从阿兹卡班逃狱
To find you.
目的就是为了找你
And kill me.
把我角了
Harry, swear to me that whatever you might hear...
我要你发将，不管你匠到什么
...you won't go looking for Black.
都不可以主动去找天狼星
Mr. Weasley...
卫斯理先生
...why would I go looking for someone who wants to kill me?
我干嘛主动去找要角我的人呢?
Quick. Quick.
快点 ! 快点 !
Oh, for goodness’ sake!
我的天啊
Don't lose him!
不要忘了忽
I didn’t mean to blow her up. I just--
我不是故意要把她吹成气球
-l lost control. -Brilliant.
-忍无可忍 -真好玩
Honestly, Ron, it’s not funny. Harry was lucky not to be expelled.
柴恩，这不好玩 哈利没被开除，就算很幸运
l was lucky not to be arrested.
谭该说很幸运我没被抓去并
I still think it was brilliant.
但我还是觉得很好玩
Come on. Everywhere else is full.
进去吧，其他车麻都满了
Who do you think that is?
这人是谁啊?
-Professor R.J. Lupin. -Do you know everything?
-路平教授 -姬条都知道
How is it she knows everything?
她为什么什么都知道 ?
-It’s on his suitcase, Ronald. -Oh.
行李上就有名字啊
-Do you think he’s really asleep? -Seems to be. Why?
-他是不是真的睡著了? -麻该是吧，干嘛?
I gotta tell you something.
有重要的事情要告诉你们
Let me get this straight. Sirius Black escaped from Azkaban...
先让我弄清楚 天狼星布莱克逃狱
-...to come after you? -Yeah.
-为了追杀你 -没错
But they'll catch Black, won't they?
可是他早晚会被抓回去
-l mean, everyone's looking for him. -Sure.
-大家都在追捕他 一 对 可可
Except no one’s ever broken out of Azkaban before...
从来没有一个人… 能锡成功逃出阿兹卡班
-...and he’s a murderous, raving lunatic. -Thanks, Ron.
-布莱克是个神经失常的兜手 -谢谢你喔，莹思
Why are we stopping?
为什么会忽然停车?
We can't be there yet.
学校还没到
What's going on?
发生什么事了?
I don’t know. Maybe we've broken down.
不知道，大概车子故障了
Ouch, Ron. That was my foot.
你踩到我的脚了
There's something moving out there.
外面有东西在支
I think someone’s coming aboard.
我觉得…好像有人上襄了
Bloody hell! What's happening?
我的天啊，到底怎和了?
Harry.
哈利!
Harry, are you all right?
哈利，你还好吧?
Thank you.
谢谢
Here, eat this. It'll help.
来，把这个吃掉，你会舒服一点
It’s all right. It's chocolate.
不要怕，这是巧克力
What was that thing that came?
刚刚那是什么…东西?
It was a dementor. One of the guards of Azkaban. It’s gone now.
那是俊狂魔，他是阿兹卡班的守和本 他已经走了
It was searching the train for Sirius Black.
他是来搜查天狼星布莱克
If you'll excuse me, I need to have a little word with the driver.
不好意思 我现在要去跟恩驶说怒句话
Eat. You'll feel better.
快吃，你会觉得好一点
What happened to me?
我是怎床了?
Well, you sort of went rigid.
你整个人都僵掉了
We thought maybe you were having a fit or something.
就像是羊癌瘦发作一样
And did either of you two...
那…你们刚刚有人也…
-...pass out? -No.
-可个吗? -没有
I felt weird, though.
只是有年奇怪的感觉
Like I'd never be cheerful again.
好像这草子再也关心不起来
But someone was screaming.
我区到有人在尖叫
A woman.
是个女的
No one was screaming, Harry.
刚刚没有人类叫
Welcome! Welcome to another year at Hogwarts.
款迎大家 来到霍格革兹度过新的一年
Now, I'd like to say a few words...
让各位失命大吃…
...before we all become too befuddled by our excellent feast.
到头昏脑月之前 我得先说烙句话
First, I'm pleased to welcome Professor R.J. Lupin...
首先，让我们欢迎路平教授
...who's kindly consented to fill the post...
他已经欣然同意接受
..of Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
黑魔法防案入教授的职位
Good luck, professor.
祝你好运，教授
Of course. That’s why he knew to give you the chocolate, Harry.
哈利，怪不得他要给你吃巧克力
Potter. Is it true you fainted?
波特 你真的展倒了?
-l mean, you actually fainted? -Shove off, Malfoy.
-我是说真的不省人事? -闭跑啦，轧份
-How did he find out? -Just forget it.
-他怎订会知道的? -不要理他
Our Care of Magical Creatures teacher...
担任奇默钻育学校教授好几年
...has decided to retire...
但是这学期他决定退休
...in order to spend more time with his remaining limbs.
好跟他残余四肢有更多时间相钴
Fortunately, I'm delighted to announce...
我现在很高典的宣做
...that his place will be taken by none other...
接替这个职位的人，正是…
...than our own Rubeus Hagrid.
我们的猎场看守人重霸海格
Finally, on a more disquieting note...
最和后，我要宣做的是…
...at the request of the Ministry of Magic...
我们收到了魔法部的要求…
..-Hogwarts will, until further notice, play host to the dementors of Azkaban...
违格革兹必须在接到进一步通知之前 要款待八名阿兹卡班的催狂魔
. until such a time as Sirius Black is captured.
直到天狼星布莱克被捕
The dementors will be stationed at every entrance to the grounds.
催狂魔将守在 韦格鞠兹所有的出入口
Now whilst I’ve been assured...
允然魔法部已经保证过
...that their presence will not disrupt our day-to-day activities...
不会让众狂魔影响我们的活动
...a word of caution.
不过大家膛是要小心
Dementors are vicious creatures. They'll not distinguish...
催狂魔知道你心中的恐悍
...between the one they hunt and the one who gets in their way.
任何侈装或幻本都驴不过他们
Therefore, 1 must warn each and every one of you...
所以我要警告你们在座的每个人
...to give them no reason to harm you.
千菌不要让他们找到理由伤害你
It is not in the nature of a dementor to be forgiving.
催狂魔对谁都不会手下留情
But you know, happiness can be found...
不过呢 我们还是可以找点乐子
..-even in the darkest of times...
引然是在这庆黑暗的时期
...if one only remembers to turn on the light.
只要点燃灯…光明就会再现
Fortuna Major.
最年长的命运女神
Here, listen. She just won't let me in.
你们看，她就是不让我进去
-Fortuna Major. -No, no. Wait, wait.
-最年长的命运女神
Watch this.
看这个
-Amazing. Just with my voice. -Fortuna Major.
-太棒了，我的歌喉真美妙 -最年长的命运女神
-Yes, all right. Go in. -Thank you.
-好了好了，进去吧 -谢谢
Still doing that after three years.
我真不敢相信她逮是没变 三年了，她还是这样斤命唱歌
-She can't even sing. -Exactly.
-她根本不会唱歌 -真是难贡死了
-Hey, man.
-嘿，你好
-Oh, God. -That’s awful.
一天啊 -真可怕
Green. That's a monkey.
是缘色，表演猴子
-What is that? -You call that a monkey?
-那是什么啊? -这也算是猴子唉?
Do not give him one again.
不要再给他吃了
Hey, Neville, try an elephant.
奈威，试试大象
-Ron, catch. -I will.
-接著，荣因 -没问题
I think we have a winner.
胶利者出现了
-Oh, don't try one of them. -Oh, no.
-不…不要再试了 -不得了
Look at him. His face.
-你看看哈利 -他的脸
Welcome, my children.
各位同学，获迎你们
In this room, you shall explore the noble art of Divination.
在这堂课里 我们将深入探索神导的占卜学
In this room, you shall discover if you possess the Sight.
只要具有透视的能力 我相信你们将会有所发现
Hello. l am Professor Trelawney.
大家好，我是崔老妮教授
Together we shall cast ourselves into the future.
我们将在这堂课程中 一起参租未来
This term, we'll focus on Tasseomancy, the art of reading tea leaves.
这学期将要学避占卜的基本技巧 就是学习如何观看茶鞭
So please, take the cup of the person sitting opposite you.
请把你对面同学的杯子拿起来
What do you see?
看到了什么?
The truth lies buried like a sentence deep within a book, waiting to be read.
真相往往被深埋起来 就像书中的字名一样，必须慢慢地阅读
But first, you must broaden your minds.
首先一定要敞开心胸
-First, you must look beyond. -What a load of rubbish.
-而目光一定要穿下现在 -真是一堆胡说八道
-Where did you come from? -Me?
你从哪儿冒出来的?
-I’ve been here all this time. -You, boy....
-我一直都在这壬啊 -孩子
Is your grandmother quite well?
你奶奶还好吧?
I think so.
应该还好吧
I wouldn't be so sure of that. Give me the cup.
我可不敢这麻肯定，杯子给我
Pity.
可异
Broaden your minds.
数开心胸
Your aura is pulsing, dear. Are you in the beyond?
你身上充满了死亡的氛息 你是不是会死呢?
-l think you are. -Sure.
-我想应该会 日 一瑟.
Look at the cup. Tell me what you see.
看杯子里面，告诉我看到什么
Yeah.
好
Harry’s got sort of a wonky cross. That's trials and suffering.
我看到哈利将会十分不平静 他将走向磨练与痛苦
And that there could be the sun and that’s happiness.
还有，我还看到了太阳 那代表一种幸福
So...
所以…
... you're gonna suffer, but you're gonna be happy about it.
他会遇到磨难 可是他会愉快接受
Give me the cup.
把杯子给我
Oh, my dear boy.
吗，我的天啊
My dear...
孩子
...you have the Grim.
你身上有…: 狗赴
The Grin? What’s the Grin?
金过 ? 什么东西金震啊?
Not the Grin, you idiot. The Grim.
不是金震啦，策蛋，是狗直
"Taking form of a giant spectral dog.
长的就像一焦大狗
It's among the darkest omens in our world.
那是最黑暗的外灰预兆
It’s an omen...
那也代表著
...of death.”
死亡
You don't think that Grim thing's got anything to do with Sirius Black?
狗起是跟天狼星有关吧?
Oh, honestly, Ron. If you ask me, Divination’s a woolly discipline.
老实说，柴恩，我觉得… 占卜学实在是很不精确的学问
Now, Ancient Runes, that’s a fascinating subject.
我认为逮是算命学 要比占下学有趣多了
Ancient Runes? Exactly how many classes are you taking?
算命学? 炼这学期到底修了多少课啊?9
A fair few.
只有一些而已啊
Hang on. That's not possible.
等一下，怎床可能?
Ancient Runes is in the same time as Divination.
算命学跟占卜学的上课时间 一模一样
You have to be in two classes at once.
你必须同时间出现在两个教室耶
Don't be silly. How could anyone be in two classes at once?
别俐了，楷思 一个人怎么可能出现在两个教室
“Broaden your minds. Use your Inner Eye to see the future.”
你要敞开心胸 用你的心起之眼看见未来啊
That’s it. Come on, now. Come closer. Less talking, if you don’t mind.
好了，各位同学，过来一点 不要再聊天了，好吗?
I got a real treat for you today.
今天的课我为你们涂备了好东西
A great lesson. So follow me.
很值得看 跟我来
Right, you lot. Less chattering. Form a group over there.
好了，不要再说话了 大家把队伍整好
And open your books to page 49.
把课本翻到第49页
Exactly how do we do that?
这本韦要怎么并啊?
Just stroke the spine, of course. Goodness me.
只要手摸书券就好啦 天啊
-Don't be such a wimp, Longbottom. -I'm okay. Okay.
-别这麻没用，隆巴顿 -我没事
-l think they're funny. -Oh, yeah. Terribly funny.
-我觉得很有趣 -有趣到嘛死人，充满了智慧
Witty. God, this place has gone to the dogs.
这个地方越来越陡落了
Wait until Father hears Dumbledore’s got this oaf teaching classes.
等我爸知道这超有个策蛋在教书 好不利多就完了
Shut up, Malfoy.
你住跑，珊份
Dementor! Dementor!
催…催狂魔…
-Just ignore him. -You're supposed to stroke it.
你应该打他才对
Yeah.
对
Isn’t he beautiful?
怨是不是很美呀?
Say hello to Buckbeak.
大家一起来跟锅跑打个招呼吧
Hagrid, exactly what is that?
海格，这是什么动物啊?
That, Ron, is a hippogriff.
这种动物叫做麻马
First thing you wanna know is they're very proud creatures.
碰到怨们的时候一定要记得 魔马的个性非常琦做
Very easily offended. You do not want to insult a hippogriff.
也很容易生气 所以千菌不要冒犯麻马
It may be the last thing you ever do.
不然你这草子就玩完了
Now, who'd like to come and say hello?
谁想来跟怨打招呼?
Well done, Harry. Well done.
很好，哈利，非常好
Come on now.
过来呀
Now...
现在你
...you have to let him make the first move. It’s only polite. So...
必须让魔马探取主动 这样才有礼貌
...step up. Give him a nice bow.
你往前一步，好好对忽鞠躬
Then you wait and see if he bows back.
然后你再看凶有没有回礼
If he does, you can go and touch him.
如果怨回礼了 你就可以放心的摸籽了
If not-- Well, we'll get to that later.
如果没有… 我们待会再说吧
Just make your bow.
现在跟煌鞠身
Nice and low.
要很有礼貌
Back off, Harry. Back off.
后退，哈利，和后退
Keep still.
继续汐著腰
Well done, Harry. Well done. Here, you big brute, you.
做得好，哈利，做得好 给你，大像伙
Right. 1 think you can go and pat him now.
好极了，你现在可以放心拍物了
Go on. Don't be shy.
眉点，别害关
Nice and slow, now. Nice and slow. Slow.
慢慢来，不要和急，慢慢的来
Not so fast, Harry.
千万不要快
Slow down, Harry. That’s it....
慢慢地来 让秃先壮近你，慢慢的…
Nice and slow. Now let him come to you.
慢慢来… 等怨壮近你
Slowly, now, slowly, slowly....
慢慢的…
That's it....
就这样…
Yes!
好极了 !
Well done! Well done, Harry, well done!
做得好，做得好，哈利!
Does he get to fly?
膛可以骑著飞一下吧?
-l think he may let you ride him now. -What?
-我想怨现在应该会让你骑了 -什么?
-Come on. -Hey, hey, hey!
-来吧 -哩1哩1哩! oo
Put you over here, just behind the wing joint.
来，我抱你上去 好好的享受这一直旅行
Don't pull out any of his feathers, because he won't thank you for that.
不要扯掉籽任何的巩毛 不然怨会不高内的
Well done, Harry, and well done, Buckbeak.
太棒了“，哈利
That was wicked, Harry!
了不起，哈利
Oh, please.
这有什么 !
Well done, well done.
太棒了“，太棒了
-How am I! doing me first day? -Brilliant, professor.
-我的第一堂课还可以吧? -太棒了了，教授
You're not dangerous at all, are you, you great ugly brute!
其实你一些都不危险 你这个醒陋的大野欧
Malfoy, no....
马份
No!
不要!
Whoa, whoa, whoa....
味1哇1!哇!
Away, you silly creature....
你这焦大策锅
-It’s killed me! -Calm down. It’s just a scratch!
-我快被凶杀了 -冷静一点，只是一点抓伤而已
Hagrid!
海格
-He has to be taken to the hospital. -I’m the teacher. I'll do it.
-快把马份送到医院里 -没错，我是老师，我有责任
-You're gonna regret this. -Class dismissed!
-我要你付出代价… -大家下课了
You and your bloody chicken!
你和那头蕉都要付出代价
Does it hurt terribly, Draco?
践哥,会不会很痛啊?
It comes and it goes. Still, 1 consider myself lucky.
怨只是嚼了一下
Madam Pomfrey said another minute and I could've lost my arm.
廉黄夫人说如果再晚个一雨分钾 我的手可能就要断掉了
-I can’t do homework for weeks. -Listen to the idiot.
-现在我一个礼拜没闪法做功课 -你们册这策蛋说的
-He’s really laying it on thick, isn't he? -At least Hagrid didn’t get fired.
-他还真会诸大其豆 -不过还好' 海格没有被开除
l hear Draco’s father’s furious. We haven't heard the end of this.
可是我匠说马份的爸爸很生气 这件事恐怕很难解决
-He’s been sighted! -Who?
-有人看到他了 ! -看到谁?
Sirius Black!
天狼星布莱克
Dufftown? That's not far from here.
达夫镇 ? 那跟郊这里很近蓝
You don’t think he’d come to Hogwarts, do you?
你党得他会来霍格革兹吗?
-With dementors at every entrance? -Dementors?
-每个出入口都有催狂魔啊 -催狂魔
He slipped past them once. Who's to say he won't do it again?
他们才让天狼星逃遇一次 谁知道会不会让他逃遇第二次
That's right. Black could be anywhere. It’s like trying to catch smoke.
疫错，他可能在任何地方 要拆住他根本不可能
Like trying to catch smoke with your bare hands.
就像用手去抓煜一样的不可能
Intriguing, isn’t it?
很好奇对不对 ?
Would anyone like to venture a guess...
有没有人要猜猜看
...as to what is inside?
里面是什么 ?
-That’s a boggart, that is. -Very good, Mr. Thomas.
-是幻形怪对不对 ? -非常好，汤玛斯先生
Now, can anybody tell me what a boggart looks like?
有人可以告诉我 幻形怪长得什么样子吗?
-No one knows. -When did she get here?
-没有人知道 -她什么时候来的?
Boggarts are shape-shifters.
幻形怪可以沁形
They take the shape of whatever a person fears the most.
他们会变成某个人最害怕的东西
-That’s what makes them so-- -So terrifying, yes, yes, yes....
-所以人们会觉得他们… -很可怕，没错…
Luckily, a very simple charm exists to repel a boggart.
很幸运的 有个简单的响语可以驱除幻形怪
Let's practice it now. Without wands, please.
我们开始练习吧, 大家先不要用魔杖
After me. Riddikulus!
跟著我叭，叱叱，荒唐
-Riddikulus! -Very good.
-叱叱，荒唐 -非常好
A little louder and very clear. Listen:
再大声一点，发音再清楚一点
-Riddikulus!
隐好，叱叱，荒唐
-This class is ridiculous. -Very good.
-这堂课逮真荒唐 -好极了
So much for the easy part. You see, the incantation alone is not enough.
其实也没那友简章 光是靠响语还不足以对付他
What really finishes a boggart is laughter.
真正解决幻形怪的法裤是… 笑声
You need to force it to assume a shape you find truly amusing.
你们必须强迫他沟成一个… 你党得好笑的形体
Let me explain. Neville, would you join me, please?
我来说明 奈威，你出来示范一下好吗?9
Come on, don't be shy. Come on.
出来啊，不要害盖，来
Come on.
来啊
Hello. Neville, what frightens you most of all?
哈唾，奈威你觉得 什么东西最可怕?
Professor Snape.
石内下教授
-Sorry? -Professor Snape.
-什么? -石内下教授
Professor Snape. Yes, frightens all.
石内卜教授? 对，他真的很可怕
-You live with your grandmother. -I don’t want it to turn into her, either.
-你是不是跟奶奶一起住啊 -是的，幻形怪变成我奶奶，我也害怕
No...
不会的
..it won't. 1 want you to picture her clothes.
我要你想像奶奶的衣服
Only her clothes, very clearly, in your mind.
只要衣服就好 ' 在心里仔细想像
-She carries a red handbag-- -We don’t need to hear.
她都拿著红色的包包 你不用说出来
As long as you see it, we'll see it. Now, when I open that wardrobe...
你只要想清楚了“，我们就会看到 等我把衣杭打开以后
.-here’s what I want you to do. Excuse me.
我要你这麻做… 不好意思
Imagine Professor Snape in your grandmother's clothes.
想著石内卜教授穿著奶奶的衣服
Can you do that?
有没有问题?
Yes. Wand at the ready.
魔杖华人备好
One, two, three.
一  一 一、 、 一
Think, Neville, think.
快想奶奶
Riddikulus!
叱叱，荒唐
Wonderful, Neville, wonderful! Incredible! Okay...
了不起，奈威，太棒了…
...to the back, Neville. Everyone, form a line....
到和后面去 ' 大家排成一列
Form a line!
排成一列
l want everyone to picture the thing they fear the very most...
我要大家先在心里面想像 最害怕的东西
..and turn it into something funny.
然后想成好笑的样子
Next! Ron!
下一个，沫思
Concentrate. Face your fear. Be brave!
专心一点，面对你的丽悍 勇敢一点
Wand at the ready, Ron.
魔杖华人备好
Riddikulus!
叱叱，荒唐
Yes!
你看吧，非常好
You see? Very good, very good!
太精采了，太精采了
Marvelous! Absolutely, very, very enjoyable! Parvati! Next!
真是非常非常的有趣 苑蒂，该你了
Show us what you see.
让我们看看你想到什么
Keep your nerve. Steady.
不要和急，慢慢来
Riddikulus!
叱叱，荒唐
And next! Step up, step up!
下一个，往前…
Wonderful, wonderful!
太讲了 !太谐了!
Here!
我来 !
Riddikulus!
叱叱，荒唐
Right. Sorry about that. That's enough for today.
非常抱歉，今天的课就到此为止
Collect your books from the back.
大家到和后面拿自己的书
That's the end of the lesson. Thank you! Sorry!
今天的课就到此为止，谢谢
Sorry, you can have too much of a good thing.
抱歉了“，大家不能张避得太这分 大家记住
Remember, these visits to Hogsmeade village are a privilege.
能金参观活米村是一种特权
Should your behavior reflect poorly on the school...
如果你们的行为破壤了校玲的话
...that privilege shall not be extended again.
就没有办法再的有这项特权了
No permission form signed, no visiting the village.
家长没有签同意书的人 不可以去参观
That's the rule, Potter.
这是规定'波特
Those with permission, follow me. Those without, stay put.
有同意书的人跟我来 没同意书的人留下
I thought if you signed it, then I could--
-只要你帮有我签名，我就可以去了 -我不能签
I can’t. Only a parent or a guardian can sign.
只有家长或监恋人才可以
Since I am neither, it would be inappropriate.
我雨者都不是，我不能
I'm sorry, Potter. That's my final word.
我很抱歉，就这广决定了
Forget about it, guys. See you later.
算了，没关像，待会见了
Professor, can Il ask you something?
教授，我可以请教你问题吗?
You want to know why I stopped you facing that boggart, yes?
-你要问为什么阻止你对付幻形怪吗? -没错
I thought it'd be obvious.
那是因为…
l assumed it would take the shape of Lord Voldemort.
我以为… 幻形怪会伙成佛地魔
I did think of Voldemort at first.
我一开始的确是想到…佛地魔
But then I remembered that night on the train...
可是我又想到火车上的情形
-...and the dementor. -I'm very impressed.
-想到催狂魔 -你很不错，这表示…
That suggests what you fear the most is fear itself.
你最丽翼的，其实是丽翼本身
This is very wise.
真是充满了智慧
Before I fainted...
我在昏倒之前
...[ heard something.
贡到了一个声音
A woman...
有个女人
. ... Screaming.
在尖叫
Dementors force us to relive our very worst memories.
催狂魔会强迫我们 回想起最恐怖的回居
Our pain becomes their power.
我们的苦痛会成为他们的能量
l think it was my mother...
我想那是我母亲…
...the night she was murdered.
被角那晚的尖叫瑶
The very first time 1 saw you, Harry, l recognized you immediately.
哈利，我第一眼看到你 就忆上知道你是谁了
Not by your scar, by your eyes.
不是因为伤疤，而是你的限卫
They're your mother, Lily’s.
就跟你母亲莉莉一样
Yes.
没错…
Oh, yes. I knew her.
没错，我认识她
Your mother was there for me at a time when no one else was.
当所有的人都不理我的时候 只有你母亲肯帮我
Not only was she a singularly gifted witch...
她不但是个充满天分的女巫
.. she was also an uncommonly kind woman.
同时她还是个非常善良的女人
She had a way of seeing the beauty in others...
不管什么时候 她总是能金看到别人的优点
...even, and most especially, when that person could not see it in themselves.
甚至，她还能金帮助别人…: 看到自己的优点
And your father, James, on the other hand...
但是，你的父亲凑姆就不一榜了
«he...
他…
He had a certain, shall we say, talent for trouble.
简直就是扔造麻烦专家
A talent, rumor has it, he passed on to you.
这个天份吡…我区说也遗传到你
You're more like them than you know, Harry.
你非常像你的父母
In time, you'll come to see just how much.
慢慢的，你就会察觉到了
Honeyduke’s Sweetshop is brilliant, but nothing beats Zonko’s Joke Shop.
蜂蜜公兽真是太棒了 但还是比不上桑科的恶作剧商店
We never got to go to the Shrieking Shack.
我们一直都找不到时间去尖叫屋
-You heard it’s the most-- -Haunted building in Britain. 1 know.
-你也知道那是全国最恐怖的鬼屋 -对，我知道
What's going on?
怎庆了?
Probably Neville forgot the password again.
大概是奈威又忘了通关密话了吧
-Hey. -Oh, you're there.
-喂! -你在这啊
Let me through, please. Excuse me! I'm Head Boy!
对不起，让我明去 不好意思，我是男生主席
Get back, all of you.
大家往和后退
No one is to enter this dormitory until it’s been searched.
在仔细搜查过之前 谁都不可以进宿舍
The Fat Lady! She’s gone!
有女士，她不见了
Serves her right. She was a terrible singer.
真是太好了，她唱歌真可怕
It’s not funny, Ron.
这一点都不好笑，莹思
Keep calm, everyone. Break into fours. Back to your common room.
冷静，各位 ! 分成四组 可到房间去
-Be quiet. -Make way.
-安静 -借过
-The headmaster’s here. -Come on, move.
-我是男生主席 -快点让并，让并
You heard. Move!
我说了，让并
Mr. Filch? Round up the ghosts.
赤七先生，把幽震都集合起来
Tell them to search every painting in the castle to find the Fat Lady.
我们要搜寻整个城堡寻找胖女士
There's no need for ghosts, professor.
教授，不用派幽起去找了
The Fat Lady’s there.
胖女士就在那里
Mind where you're going! Slow down!
你们要去哪里，停下来
You listen! I'm Head Boy!
隐我说，我是男生主席
-Come back here! -Keep moving!
-快点回来啦 -继续前进
Dear lady, who did this to you?
亲党的胖女士，是谁这样对人?
Eyes like the devil, he’s got, and a soul as dark as his name.
他的眼神就像佘魔一样息怖 起魂就跟他的人一样黑暗
It’s him, headmaster. The one they all talk about.
是他，校长 就是大家说的那个人
He’s here, somewhere in the castle!
他在这儿，在城堡里面
Sirius Black!
天狼星布莱克
Secure the castle, Mr. Filch. The rest of you, to the Great Hall.
悉七，封锁整个城保 所有同学都到大廉去
I've searched the Astronomy Tower and the Owlery. There’s nothing there.
我搜基了天文塔还有猪头魔房 但是什么都没有
-Thank you. -The third floor’s clear too, sir.
-谢谢 -三楼也完全徽查过了
-Very good. -l’ve done the dungeons.
-很好 -我也搜过地牢了
No sign of Black, nor anywhere else in the castle.
天狼星不在那里 整座城堡都找不到他
I didn’t really expect him to linger.
我想他应该不会在这儿运留
Remarkable feat, don’t you think?
他膛真的很属害
To enter Hogwarts Castle on one’s own...
竟然可以一个人泪入霍格药辫
-...completely undetected? -Quite remarkable, yes.
-没有被人发现 -的确是很属害
Any theories on how he managed it?
你能想到他是怎么做到的吗 ?
Many. Each as unlikely as the next.
有很多方式，但是都行不通
You may recall...
您应该还记得
...prior to the start of term l expressed concerns...
学期并始之前 我对你聘用
..-about your appointment of Professor--
路平教授 感到非常担心
Not a single professor inside this castle would help Sirius Black enter it.
学校里所有的教授 都不会是天狼星的内麻
I'm quite convinced the castle is safe...
我想现在城堡已经安全了
..and I’m more than willing to send the students to their houses.
所有同学都可以回自己学院去了
What about Potter? Should he be warned?
那波特呢? 要警告他吗?
Perhaps. But for now, let him sleep.
或许吧，不过现在先让他睡一下
For in dreams, we enter a world that's entirely our own.
只要进入欧乡 就完全是属於自己的世界
Let them swim in the deepest ocean or glide over the highest cloud.
我们可以在深海里头悠游 也可以在云端上番翔
Turn to page 394.
翻到课本第39 4页
Excuse me, sir. Where's Professor Lupin?
对不起，教授 请问路平教授怎厌了?
That's not really your concern, is it, Potter?
这不关你的事，不是吧，波特?
Suffice it to say your professor finds himself incapable of teaching...
简单的说，你们的教授 目前暂时没有能力教导你们
...at the present time. Turn to page 394.
请翻开课本3 9 4页
"Werewolves"?
狼人?
Sir, we just learned about red caps and hinkypunks.
可是教授… 我们才刚学到红坎帽跟上哼即帮
-We’re not meant to start that for weeks. -Quiet.
-还要好绑个礼拜才会教夜行动物 -安静
When did she come in? Did you see her come in?
她从哪冒出来的? 你有看到她进来吗?
Now, which one of you can tell me the difference...
你们谁能告诉我 化葡师…
... between an Animagus and a werewolf?
跟狼人之癌的差恰
No one?
都不知道?
-How disappointing. -Please, sir.
-真是令人失望 -我知道，教授
An Animagus is a wizard who elects to turn into an animal.
化葡师是自己选择伙成狼的巫师
A werewolf has no choice.
狼人他则是没有选择的
With each full moon...
每到满月的时候他就会变身
...he no longer remembers who he is. He'd kill his best friend.
这时候他会忘了自己是谁 还会不知情的角死最好的朋友
The werewolf only responds to the call of its own kind.
狼人他只会回应狼人的呼叫而已
Thank you, Mr. Malfoy. That's the second time...
谢谢你，珊份先生
..-you've spoken out of turn, Miss Granger.
格荫像小姐 这是你第二次擅自发言
Are you incapable of restraining yourself...
你就不能克制一点吗?
...or do you take pride in being an insufferable know-it-all?
自以为了不起的菌事通
-He’s got a point, you know. -Five points from Gryffindor.
-他还算有点道理 -葛莱分多扣五分
As an antidote to your ignorance, and on my desk, by Monday morning...
为了治疗你们的狂妄自大 礼拜一早上之前
...two rolls of parchment on the werewolf, with emphasis...
要交给我雨捍羊皮纸的狼人报告
-...0n recognizing it. -It’s Quidditch tomorrow.
-主题要放在如何辩识狼人 -明天有爸地奇比赛
Then I suggest you take extra care, Mr. Potter.
那我建议你最好特别小心 波特先生
Loss of limb will not excuse you.
就算手摔断了也要交作业
Page 394.
翻到课本第39 4页
The term "werewolf"...
狼人这个名词
. is a contraction of the Anglo-Saxon word "wer"...
字源来自邢格鲁节克肝 到也民刁这个字…
...which means "man," and "wolf." Werewolf, man-wolf.
代表“人 “狼人”的意思就是像人的狼
There are several ways to become a werewolf.
狼人的形成包括…
They include being given the power of shape-shifting...
自己变形的…
... being bitten by a werewolf....
被狼人咬和后变身
Go, Harry! Go, Harry!
-加油，哈利…
Aresto momentum!
动作慢下来…
-He looks a bit peaky, doesn't he? -Peaky?
-他看起来好虚弱哩 -虚弱?
What do you expect? He fell over 100 feet.
他这样已经不错了 他和从一百黄只高掉下来陡
Let's walk you off a tower and see what you look like.
把你从天文塔上丢下来 看你会成什么德性
Probably a right sight better than he normally does.
搞不好会变得比现在钟
-How are you feeling? -Oh, brilliant.
-你党得怎大样? -喔，还好啦
You gave us a right good scare.
你真的快把我们嘛死了
-What happened? -Well, you fell off your broom.
-发生什么事了? -你从赤天抬壳上面掉下来
Really? ! meant the match. Who won?
真的，那比赛，谁赢了?
No one blames you, Harry.
哈利，没有人会责怪你
Dementors aren't supposed to be on the grounds. Dumbledore’s furious.
是催狂魔不该到比赛场地来的 好不利多非常生气
After he saved you, he sent them off.
他救了你之和后 马上就叫俊狂魔郊天
There's something else you should know too.
还有一件事要告诉你，哈利
When you fell, your broom sort of blew into the Whomping Willow, and....
你掉下来之和后，你的抬壳… 被吹到淖拼柳那里去
i'm sorry to hear about your broomstick.
我观说站天择需的事情了
Is there no chance of fixing it?
真的没闪法修好吗?
No.
没有
Professor, why do the dementors affect me so?
为什么催狂魔对我影响这文大?
-l mean, more than everyone else? -Listen.
我是说，其他人都不会这样
Dementors are the foulest creatures to walk this earth.
催狂魔是这世界上最丽怖的生物
They feed on every good feeling, every happy memory...
他们会吸食人类的快乐泉源
...until a person is left with absolutely nothing but his worst experiences.
直到一个人除了可怕的回居之外 其他的一乱所有
You are not weak, Harry.
你一点也不软弱，哈利
Dementors affect you most because there are true horrors in your past.
催狂魔对你的影响这广大 是因为你过去的经历太恐怖
Horrors your classmates can scarcely imagine.
那是你的同学们扰法想像的经于
You have nothing to be ashamed of.
你一点也不需要感到姜取
-I'm scared, professor. -I'd consider you a fool if you weren't.
-可是我很害怕，教授 -只有傻瓜才不会害怕
I need to know how to fight them. You could teach me.
我想知道该怎庆击退他们 你可以教我
You made the one on the train go away.
你在火车上击退了催狂魔
There was only one that night.
因为只有一个催狂魔
-But you made it go away. -l don’t pretend to be an expert, Harry.
-可是你超走他了 -哈利，冰不是我想要自抬身价
But as the dementors seem to have developed an interest in you...
既然催狂魔他对你这广有检趣
...perhaps I should teach you. But after the holidays.
不过得等村诞节之和后
For now, I need to rest.
目前，我得好好休息
-Guys, let me go. -Clever, Harry.
-你们放开我啤… -你很机赴，哈利
-But not clever enough. -We've got a better way.
-不过还不欧机团 -幸好我们有好东西
-I'm trying to get to Hogsmeade. -We know.
-和拜斌，我正在设法去活米村 -我们知道
We'll get you there.
-别担心 -我们会帮你
-We'll show you a quicker way. -If you pipe down.
-有一人条特别捷径 -不过你要先冷静
-Bless him. -Let me go! Come on, guys. Don’'t--
-上帝保估 -好啦，放天我啦，拜斌
-Now, Harry. -Come and join the big boys.
好了“，哈利 加入大哥哥的阵容吧
What are you doing?!
你们在干嘛?
-What's this rubbish? -"What's this rubbish?” he says.
-这什么灿东西啊? -他说这是痣东西耶
-It’s the secret to our success. -It’s a wrench giving it to you--
-这可是我们成功的秘密唱 -送给你我们可是很心疼的
But we've decided your needs are greater than ours.
不过我们决定 你比我们还需要
George, if you will.
备治，开始吧
l solemnly swear that 1 am up to no good.
我在此郑重发将，我绝不怀好意
“Messrs. Moony, Wormtail, Padfoot and Prongs...
在此月影、右尾、葡足与鹿角…
...are proud to present the Marauder’s Map.”
上玲推出劫旨地图
We owe them so much.
我们久他们太多了
Hang on. This is Hogwarts. And that--
等一下，这是堆格竺区 还有这是…
-No. Is that really--? -Dumbledore.
-不会吧，这真的是… -好不利多
-In his study. -Pacing.
-在书房里头 -踊步…
Does that a lot.
他常这样
-So this map shows--? -Everyone.
-这地图可以看到… -所有的人
-Where they are. -What they're doing.
-他们在哪… -在做什么…
-Every minute. -Every day.
-任何时间… -每天都可以
-Brilliant! Where did you get it? -From Filch’s office.
-太棒了，你从哪儿型来的? -我们在一年级的时候
-First year. -There are seven secret passageways...
-从屡七的办公室偷出来的 -在学校里面总共有七休密道
-The One-Eyed Witch passageway. -Leads you to Honeyduke’s.
-独眼醒老女巫密道 -直通活米村
Hurry. Filch is heading this way.
不过动作要快，屡七正往这下走
And don't forget. When you're done, just give it a tap and say:
吗，不要忘了 等你用完之后，要拍一下然后说
“Mischief managed.” Otherwise, anyone can read it.
“恶作央完成“ 不然别人会看到里头的文字
Delicious.
好吃
It’s meant to be the most haunted building in Britain. Did 1 mention that?
真不愧是全英国最丽怖的鬼屋 我有没有跟你说过 ?
Twice.
两次了
Do you want to move a bit closer?
你要不要走近一点 ?
To the Shrieking Shack?
再接近尖叫屋一点啊
Actually, I’m fine here.
不用了，我在这壬就好了
Well, well. Look who's here.
看看是谁在这啊
You two shopping for your new dream home?
你正在看心中梦想的小屋吧?
Bit grand for you, isn’t it, Weasle-Bee? Don't your family sleep in one room?
你应该买不起吧, 你们全家不是都扩在同一个房间
-Shut your mouth, Malfoy. -Not very friendly.
-闭嘴，马份 -真没礼貌
Boys, I think it’s time we teach Weasle-Bee how to respect his superiors.
兄弟，我们该好好教教本斯理 怎么尊重上流社会的人
-Hope you don't mean yourself. -How dare you talk to me!
-希望你不是在说你自己 -称没资格跟我说话
You filthy little mudblood!
你这焦可情的麻生
Who is that?
谁呵?
-Don’t stand there! Do something! -What?
不要发呆，快帮有我
What’s up, Malfoy? Lost your skis?
怎床了，马份? 雪要挤了?
Get out of the way!
滚开
Malfoy! Wait! Wait!
轧份 ! 等我 !
Harry!
哈利
Bloody hell, Harry. That was not funny.
可显啊，哈利 一点也不好玩
Those weasels! Never told me about any Marauder’s Map.
他们雨个壤蛋 从来没有跟我说劫次地图的事
He won't keep it. He'll turn it over to Professor McGonagall.
哈利，你不会留下地图吧 你会把地图交给故教授
-Aren't you? -Sure. Along with his Invisibility Cloak.
-对不对? -是吗，膛会速隐形斗篷一起交出去
Look who it is. Madam Rosmerta.
你们看这是谁，路梅塔夫人慎
-Ron fancies her. -That’s not true!
-此思在暗继她喔 -别筷讲
-Professor McGonagall! -Cornelius!
-鹤教授 -康尼留斯
Allow me, minister.
让我来，部长
-Oh, Hagrid.... -Sorry about that.
-哦，海格 ! -抱菊了
Rosmerta, my dear. I hope business is good.
亲党的中梅塔，的生意逮好吧
It'd be a lot better if the Ministry wasn't sending dementors...
如果魔法部不要每天晚上，… 派催狂魔来我店里巡愧
-...into my pub every other night! -We have....
-我的生意会好得不得了 -没法子…
-We have a killer on the loose. -Sirius Black in Hogsmeade!
-我们在追捕杀人犯 -天狼星布莱克在活米村
And what would bring him here?
他来这里干什么 ?
-Harry Potter. -Harry Potter?
-哈利波特 -哈利波特?
Come.
进去
Harry!
哈利!
-No underage wizards allowed in today! -Shut the damn door!
-未成年的人今天不可以进来 -把门关起来
-So rude. -Thick heads.
-好没礼貌 -讨厥抑
-Thick heads?! -How dare they!
-讨厥抑? -好大的脆 !
-Who are they calling thick heads? -Young whippersnappers!
-他们在说你是讨屡彼 -小鬼头
Nobody will come to a pub where they'll get scared out of their wits.
催狂魔害得大家不敢来酒吧 除非他们想被嘛得半死
Professor Dumbledore doesn’t want dementors around the place.
好不利多教授根本不想这样 到让都是催狂魔
Tell me what this is all about.
好吧，告诉我到底是怎麻回事
Years ago, when Harry Potter’s parents realized they were marked for death--
很多年以前，当哈利波特的父母 知道自己被追杀时
Remember? They hid. Few knew where they were.
就躲到了一个地方 只有猎人个人知道他们在哪
One who did was Sirius Black. And he told You-Know-Who.
包括了天狼星布莱克 但是他告诉了你知道的那个人
Not only did Black lead him to the Potters that night...
天狼星那天晚上 不但带那个人找到了波特
...he also killed Peter Pettigrew!
还角了另一个好朋友彼得佩迪鲁
-Peter Pettigrew? -Little lump of a boy.
-谁是彼得佩迪甸? -他是个不起眼的小男孩
-Always trailing after Black. -l remember.
-老是跟在天狼星屁股和后头 -我想起来了
Never let James and Sirius out of his sight.
老是跟著他们
-What happened? -Peter tried to warn the Potters...
-这跟他有什么关父? -彼得佩迪入想警告波特
..and might have, had he not run into an old friend, Sirius Black.
他本来可以成功的，要不是他 先去找了他们的好朋友天狼星布莱克
Black was vicious. He didn’t kill Pettigrew.
天狼星非常邪恶 他不只负了佩迪生
He destroyed him!
他甚至毁属减踊
A finger. That’s all that was left. A finger. Nothing else.
只剩手指，佩迪久只剩下一根手指 其他全没了
Sirius Black may not have put his hands to the Potters...
路然不是天狼星亲自下手
-...but he’s the reason they're dead. -He wants to finish things.
-但波特夫女人钾是因他而死 -现在他打算新革除根
-I don’t believe it. -That’s not the worst of it.
-我不相信
-What could be worse? -This: Sirius Black was...
-还有什么更粳的 -天狼星布莱克…
..-and remains to this day...
直到现在都还是…
...Harry Potter's godfather!
还是哈利波特的教父
Ron, look!
此思，你看
-Sorry. Excuse me, excuse me. -Merry Christmas.
-不好意思，借通… -本诞快乐
Harry, what happened?
哈利，怎麻了?
He was their friend...
他是他们的好朋友
...and he betrayed them.
但是他背叛他们
He was their friend!
他们是好朋友
l hope he finds me.
我希望他超快找到我
Because when he does, I'm gonna be ready!
到那个时候，我已经准备好了
When he does, I'm gonna kill him!
等他来找我，我就妆了他
Harry.
哈利?
There you are. You came.
你来了
Are you sure about this, Harry? This is very advanced magic...
你真的要学这个吗 ? 这可是很高深的巫术
..-well beyond the Ordinary Wizarding Level.
已经超过了普通巫术的等级
I'm sure.
我要学
Well, everything's prepared.
一切都准备好了
The spell I'm going to teach you is called the Patronus Charm.
我现在要教你的这个咒语 叫做访法加
Did you ever hear of it?
你有没有区过?
No? Well....
没有啊
A Patronus is a positive force. For the wizard who conjures one...
访法响是一种正面的能量 召唤出这个法术的巫师
. it works like a shield, with the dementor feeding on it rather than him.
在面对催狂魔的时候 就等从有了一道屏障
But in order for it to work, you need to think of a memory.
可是要施展这道巫征 必须想著快乐的回忆
Not just any memory, a very happy memory, a very powerful memory.
不是一般的回居 必须非常快乐，非常有力的回居
Can you do this? Yes. Very well.
你做得到吗 了 好，非常好
Close your eyes.
六上你的限贞
Concentrate.
要专心
Explore your past.
探索你的过去
Do you have a memory?
有想起什么回居吧?
Allow it to fill you up.
让自己充满回居
Lose yourself within it.
完全沉缅其中
Then speak the incantation, Expecto Patronum.
好，天始叭这个咒语 疾疾，访法现身
-Expecto Patronum. -Very good.
-疾疾，访法现身 -非常好
Shall we? Wand at the ready.
好了邑?9 魔杖华人备好
Expecto Patronum!
疾疾，访法现身
Expecto.... Expecto....
疾疾…… 了 疾疾……
Expect....
疾疾……
Here we go. Come on. Sit up. Deep breaths.
好了，来，坐好 深呼吸
It’s all right. I didn’t expect you to do it the first time.
没关俐 没有人第一次针习就能学会
That would have been remarkable. Here, eat this. You'll feel better.
那会是很不得了的成就 吃下去，你会党得舒服一点
-That’s one nasty dementor. -Oh, no, no, no.
这个催狂魔好属害 不
That was a boggart, Harry. A boggart.
这个只是幻形怪而已
The real thing would be worse. Much, much worse.
真的催狂魔比这个还恐怖 恐怖多了
As a matter of interest, what were you thinking?
我觉得很好奇，你刚刚在想什么
-Which memory did you choose? -The first time I rode a broom.
你选用了什么愉快的回居 我第一次骑屡天抬壳
That's not good enough. Not nearly good enough.
这回收不统恰快，效果还不金强
There's another. It’s not happy, exactly.
还有其他回居 可是那不算…快乐的事
Well, it is.
那是我…
It’s the happiest I've ever felt...
这草子最快乐的回剧
-...but it's complicated. -Is it strong?
-感受很复杂 -很强烈吗?
Then let's give it a try. You feel ready?
那我们来试试看吧 你准备好了吗?
Just do it.
开始吧
Expecto Patronum!
疾疾，访法现身
Yes!
太好了
Well done, Harry. Well done!
哈利，做得好，做得好
-l think I’ve had enough for today. -Yes. Sit down. Here.
-我觉得今天的张避已经约了 -是啊，坐下来
Eat this, it helps. It really helps.
来，吃下去，你会比较舒服
And just so you know, Harry...
我得告诉你，哈利
...[ think you’d have given your father a run for his money. And that...
你罗列的表现让我想起你父亲
..is saying something.
真的让我想起他了…
I was thinking of him.
我就是在想他
And Mum.
还有我妈
Seeing their faces.
回居他们的样子
They were talking to me.
还有他们跟我说话
Just talking.
不停的说话
That's the memory I chose.
那是我选择的回居
I don’t even know if it’s real.
我不知道那是不是真的
But it’s the best I have.
可是那是最好的
-Beautiful day. -Gorgeous.
-好美的天气 -是很美
Unless you've been ripped to pieces!
希望你没把怨骨头拆掉
Ripped to pieces? What are you talking about?
把骨头拆掉 ? 这什么意思啊?
-Ronald has lost his rat. -l haven't lost anything!
-柴思的宅物老鼠不见了 -和拖才不是不见
-Your cat killed him! -Rubbish.
-是被你的猫角了 -胡说
Harry, you've seen the way that bloodthirsty beast of hers...
你也知道她那头丽怖的猫
..is always lurking about. And Scabbers is gone.
老是在附近跑来跑去 现在斑斑又不见了
Well, maybe you should take better care of your pets!
是你自己该学著照闯自己的坷物
-Your cat killed him! -Did not.
-和拖被你的猫杀掉了 -才没有
-Did. -Didn’t.
一虹有
How did it go, Hagrid? The hearing?
海格，隐证会进行得怎样了?
Well, first off, the committee members took turns...
这个嘛，一开始所有的成员
...talking about why we were there.
先说明开贡证会的原因
I got up and did my piece. Said how Buckbeak...
然后我起来说明，锅跑是…
...was a good hippogriff, always cleaned his feathers.
很乱的一焦魔遍 凶都会把巩毛清乾漳
And then Lucius Malfoy got up. Well, you can imagine.
接著，重体斯马份就站起来 你们订该想像得到
He said Buckbeak was a deadly and dangerous creature...
他说高嘴是危险又致命的动物
..-who would kill you as soon as look at you.
看到任何人就想马上角死对方
And then?
结果呢?
And then he asked for the worst, did old Lucius.
结果重休斯提出了最鼠属的要求
-They’re not sacking you! -No, I'm not sacked.
-们不是要开除你吧 -不，我没有被开除
Buckbeak’s been sentenced to death!
高踢被判处死刑
Spiders! There’s-- There's spiders. Spiders. They want me to tap-dance.
有殉蛛，怨们要我跳舞
-l don’t wanna tap-dance! -You tell those spiders.
-我不要跳舞 -你要对抗煌们
Right, yeah. Tell them. I'll tell them....
吗，对，对抗季们 对抗怨们，明天再对抗
-Peter Pettigrew? -Little lump of a boy.
-彼得佩迪重? -他是个不起眼的小男孩
-Always trailing after Sirius Black. -Black was vicious.
-老是跟在天狼星屁股和后头 -天狼星非常邪恶
He didn't kill Pettigrew, he destroyed him!
他不只负了佩迪生 他甚至毁属减踊
-Put that light out! -Sorry.
-把粒关掉 -对不起
-Watch it there, boy. -We're trying to sleep here!
-小心一点，同学 -我们还想要睡党呢
Mischief managed. Nox.
显作剧完成，啊刻斯
Potter.
波特
What are you doing wandering the corridors at night?
怎订这废晚了还在走廊上筹荡
I was sleepwalking.
我在欧遂
How extraordinarily like your father you are, Potter.
你逮真的很像你爸爸
He, too, was exceedingly arrogant, strutting about the castle.
你们一样傲慢无礼… 在学校里目中无人
My dad didn’t strut. And nor do I.
我爸他才没有目中乱人 我也没有
Now, if you don’t mind, I would appreciate it if you could lower your wand.
如果你不介意的话 请你把魔杖放低一点
Turn out your pockets.
把东西拿出来
Turn out your pockets!
口袋的东西…拿出来
What's this?
这是什么 ?
-Spare bit of parchment. -Really? Open it.
-用剩的羊皮纸 -真的吗 ? 打开
Reveal your secrets.
把秘密现出来
“Messrs. Moony, Wormtail, Padfoot, and Prongs...
月影，串尾' 软足与鹿角囚位先生
...offer their compliments to Professor Snape and...."
在此大力讲赏石办卜教授
Go on.
继续哈
“And request he keep his large nose out of other people’s business.”
请他带著他的超级大鼻子走开 不要多管六事
-You insolent little-- -Professor!
-你这个合慢扰礼的… -教授
Well, well. Lupin.
吗…喔，是路平
Out for a little walk in the moonlight, are we?
你是出来散步，欣赏满月的吗?
Harry, are you all right?
哈利，你还好吧?
That remains to be seen.
恐怕很难说吧
Il have now just confiscated a rather curious artifact.
我刚刚从波特身上 没收了一个很有趣的艺术品
Take a look, Lupin. Supposed to be your area of expertise.
你看看 这麻该是属於你的专业领域
-Clearly, it’s full of dark magic. -l seriously doubt it, Severus.
-很明显的这跟黑魔法有关 -这恐怕不见得喔，教授
It looks as though it’s a parchment designed to insult anyone...
在我看来，这个羊皮纸卷 只是被设计成打算污情所有…
...who tries to read it. I suspect it's a Zonko product.
设法阅读羊皮纸卷的人 我想这是从活米村买来的
Nevertheless, I shall investigate any hidden qualities it may possess.
不过呢，我还是得检查 看看里头有没有什么黑暗力量
It is, after all, as you say, my area of expertise.
就如你说的，这是我的专业领域
Harry, would you come with me, please? Professor, good night.
哈利，请你跟我一起来好吗? 晚安了，教授
Are you deaf? Put that light out!
你是声子吗 ? 把灯关掉啦
Come in.
进来
Il haven't the faintest idea how this map came to be in your possession...
我完全没有头绪 不知道这个地图怎庆会在你手上
...but quite frankly, 1 am astounded that you didn't hand it in.
不过说句老实话 我很车证你竟然没有把它交出来
Did it never occur to you that this, in the hands of Sirius Black...
你交道没想过这地图 很可能来自…
...is a map to you?
天狼星布莱克吗?
-No. -No, sir.
-没有 -没有，教授
Your father never set much store by the rules either.
你爸爸的确是很少遵守规则
But he and your mother gave their lives to save yours.
可是他跟你姻为了救你 而粕牲了自己的生命
Gambling their sacrifice by wandering the castle unprotected...
你夜晚在城堡六荡 等於是在冒生命危险
..-with a killer on the loose seems to me a poor way to repay them!
让名手对你有机可乘 这实在不是回报你父母的好方式
Now, I will not cover up for you again.
我下次不会再帮你掩饰了
-Do you hear me? -Yes, sir.
-匠到了没有? -区到了
l want you to return to your dormitory and stay there.
我要你回到宿舍去，不准离开
And don't take any detours. If you do, I shall know.
不准再绕到别的地方去 如果你乱跑，我会知道的
Professor, just so you know, I don't think that map always works.
教授，我必须告诉你 这个地图不是永下那麻准确
Earlier, it showed someone in the castle. Someone I know to be dead.
刚刚地图指出一个人出现在城堡 可是我知道那个人已经死了
Oh, really? And who might that be?
真的?那个人是谁?
Peter Pettigrew.
彼得佩迪和鲁
That's not possible.
不可能啊
It's just what I saw.
我真的看到了
Good night, professor.
晚安，教授
Broaden your minds. You must look beyond.
数开你的心胸 而是光一定要穿越现在
The art of crystal gazing is in the clearing of the Inner Eye.
只有清激的心赴之眼 才能看穿水晶球
Only then can you see. Try again.
才能金看选未来，再试一次
Now, what do we have here?
这里出现了什么 ?
Do you mind me trying?
可以让我试试看吧?
The Grim, possibly.
好像是…狗夫
My dear, from the first moment you stepped foot in my class...
亲爱的 从第一次踏进我这问教室开始
...l sensed that you did not possess the proper spirit...
我就知道其实你根本就不具备…
..-for the noble art of Divination. No, you see, there.
学习这门高贵占卜学的者魂 不集看看
You may be young in years, but your heart is as shriveled...
你的外表是很年轻没错 但是内在的你
...as an old maid’s, your soul as dry as the pages of the books...
估扩有老女人枯竭的埠魂 你的过瑰就跟书页一样的乾枯
...to which you so desperately cleave.
再怎庆努力也读不出未来
Have I said something?
我说错话了吗?
She's gone mental, Hermione has. Not that she wasn't always mental...
妙林她真的疯了 以前她从来没有这麻不正常
...but now it’s in the open for everyone to see.
不过现在很明显 大家都看得出来
Hang on.
等一下
-We better take this back. -l'm not going back.
-我要把这拿回去 -我才不要回去啊
-Fine. See you later. -See you.
-好吧，待会见 -待会见
Harry Potter....
哈利波特…
-Professor Trelawney-- -He will return tonight.
-誉老妮教授 -他将会在今晚回来
Sorry?
什么?
Tonight, he who betrayed his friends, whose heart rots with murder...
今晚，那个背叛朋友的人 心赴被腐扰的级人听手
..-Shall break free.
会平安逃走
Innocent blood shall be spilt...
扰享的人会流下鲜血
..and servant and master shall be reunited once more.
奴仪跟主人十个会再一次相镍
I'm so sorry, dear boy. Did you say something?
对不起啊，和孩子 你加加有说什么吗?
No.
没有
Nothing.
没什让
I can’t believe they're going to kill Buckbeak. It’s just too horrible.
我真不敢相信他们要儿了和饥嘴 太可恶了
-It just got worse. -What did I say? Father said...
-讨厥鬼来了 -我爸说
...[ can keep the hippogriff’s head. I'll donate it to the Gryffindors’ room.
我可以收藏魔马的头 我想我会把头捐给葛莱分多的交谊廉
This is going to be rich.
这一定很好玩
-Look who’s here. -Come to see the show?
-看谁来了 -来参秽处决的吗?
Hermione, no!
妙采，不要
He’s not worth it.
他不值得你动手
Malfoy, are you okay?
图份，你没事吧?
-Let’s go. Quick. -Not a word to anyone, understood?
-快走.… -别说出去 !
-That felt good. -Not good, brilliant.
-感觉真好 -不是好，是岂采了
Look at him. Loves the smell of the trees when the wind blows through them.
你们看看忽 名最训获并微风吹来的构木味道
Why don't we just set him free?
为什么不能偷偷放生走呢?
They'd know it was me, and then Dumbledore...
他们会知道是我做的 然后好不利多
... would get into trouble. He’s coming down, Dumbledore.
就有麻烦了 好不利多等会儿会来
Says he wants to be with me when they....
他说他要陪我度过…
When it happens.
度过那一刻
Great man, Dumbledore.
他真是个好人
A great man.
了不起的好人
-We'll stay with you too. -You'll do no such thing!
-海格，我们也会陪著你 -你们不可以这广做
Think I want you seeing something like that? No.
不能让你们目睹那种事，不行
You just drink your tea and be off. Oh. Before you do, Ron....
你们把茶喝完和后就回去 在这之前，荣轧…
Scabbers! You're alive!
斑斑，你还活著
-Keep a closer eye on your pet. -l think you owe someone an apology.
-你要好好果住自己的窜物 -我想这代表你必须跟菜人道歉
Right. Next time 1 see Crookshanks, Pll let him know.
下次看到牌腿的时候 我会跟他道歉的
I meant me!
我是说我
Blimey. What was that?
天啊，是谁啊?
Hagrid!
海格
Oh, crikey.
天啊
No, minister. Over this way.
不，部长，请走这逮
It’s late. It’s nearly dark. You shouldn't be here.
已经晚了，天快黑了 你们赶快走吧
Someone sees you outside this time of night, you'll be in trouble.
这刻晚示被人发现在城堡外面 你们会有麻烦的
Particularly you, Harry. With you in a moment!
尤其是你，哈利 我局上就来了
Quick. Quick!
快走，快走
Hagrid.
海格
-It'll be fine. It'll be okay. -Go on, go on!
-一定会没事的，不会有事的 -快走
-That’s ling you see over there-- -On the slope.
-你们在那里看到的是石南顶莱 -在斜坡上
-On the slope-- Ah, Hagrid. -Professor Dumbledore.
-在斜坡上…海格 -好不利多教授
-Good evening. -Minister. Make your way through.
-晚安 -部长，请到这录来
-Have a tea, if you like. -No, Hagrid.
-要不要喝杯茶啊? -不用，海格
-Gentlemen. -I'd like a cup of tea.
-先生们 -我想喝杯茶
Well, I think we should get down to our business, shall we?
好，我们订该言贤正传了吧 是不是?
Very well. It is the decision of the Committee for the Disposal...
委员会已经做出决定
...of Dangerous Creatures that the hippogriff Buckbeak...
要除掉这头危险的生物
. hereinafter called "the condemned,” shall be executed this day at sundown.
这个叫做高嘴的魔马 今天日落前我们就必须处决
-Dear, dear.... -Now, now, Hagrid. Now, come on.
-亲党的，求求你… -海格，不要，别这样
-All right. It'll be all right. -The execution shall dispatch--
-好吧，就这样子 -处决即胖於…
What?
怎庆了?
I thought I just saw--
我蜀蜀好像看到…
-Never mind. -Let’s go!
-没什么 -我们走吧,
Buckbeak didn’t mean no harm.
高嘴不会故意伤害人的
Oh, no.
哦，不要
He bit me. Scabbers.
和儿咬我，斑斑
Ron. Ron!
沫思，荣因
-Ron! -Scabbers, come back.
-此思 -斑班，快回来
Wait!
等一下
-Scabbers, you bit me! -Harry, you do realize what tree this is?
-斑斑，你咬我 -哈利，你知道这是什么橱吗 ?
That's not good. Ron, run!
不妙了，荣思快跑
Harry, Hermione, run!
哈利，妙林，快跑
It’s the Grim!
是狗震
-Harry! -Ron! Ron, wait!
-哈利 -楷恩…等一下
Harry!
哈利
-Help! -Ron!
救我 !
-Ron. Ron.
-此思，荣因 -柴思 !
Come on!
快走
Move!
内并
Duck!
趴下
Harry!
哈利!
-Oh, I’m sorry. -Don't worry.
-对不起 -没关像
-Where do you suppose this goes? -l have a hunch.
-你觉得这里会通到哪里? -我有个预感
I just hope I’m wrong.
希望我错了
We're in the Shrieking Shack, aren't we?
我们现在是在尖叫屋，对不对 ?
Come on.
来吧
Ron.
某思
-Ron. You're okay. -The dog. Where is it?
-此轧，你没事吧? -那焦狗在哪里?
It’s a trap. He’s the dog. He’s an Animagus.
他就是狗，他是化葡师
If you want to kill Harry, you have to kill us too!
你要角哈利，得先把我们杀掉
No. Only one will die tonight.
不，今天晚上只有一个人会死
Then it'll be you!
那个人就是你
Are you going to kill me, Harry?
你真的要条我中，哈利?
Well, well, Sirius. Looking rather ragged, aren't we?
天狼星啊天狼星! 我们看起来好激动啊
Finally, the flesh reflects the madness within.
我们终於能表达出疯狂的内在了
Well, you'd know all about the madness within, wouldn't you?
你最了解况狂的内在是什么样子 不是吐，路平?
-l found him. -l know.
-我找到他了 -是的
-He’s here. -l understand.
-他就在这壬 -我了解
-Let’s kill him! -No! I trusted you!
-快把他负了吧 -不，我那庆地信任你
And all this time, you've been his friend.
结果…你一直都在接应他
He's a werewolf! That's why he’s been missing classes.
他是狼人，所以他才不能去上课
How long have you known?
你什么时候知道的?
-Since Professor Snape set the essay. -Well, Hermione.
写完石内卜教授规定的报告以后
You are the brightest witch of your age I’ve ever met.
炼真是我所见过这个年纪丑 最隐明的女巫
Enough talk, Remus! Come on, let’s kill him!
不要再广话' 路平，快把他欠了
-Wait! -l did my waiting!
-等一下 -我已经等很久了
Twelve years of it!
我在阿兹卡班…
In Azkaban!
等了十二年
Very well. Kill him.
好吧…那就角吧
But wait one more minute. Harry has the right to know why.
可是你得再等一下 哈利有权利知道原因
I know why.
我早就知道了
You betrayed my parents.
他背叛了我爸杂
-You're the reason they're dead! -No, it wasn’t him.
-他们会死都是因为他 -不，哈利，那不是他
Somebody did betray your parents...
的确是有人背叛了你的父母
...somebody who, until quite recently, I believed to be dead!
可是一直到现在我们都以为… 那个人已经死了
-Who was it, then? -Peter Pettigrew!
-那个人是谁? -彼得佩迪香
And he’s in this room! Right now!
而他现在就在这里
Come out, come out, Peter!
出来…出来吧，彼得
-Come out, come out and play! -Expelliarmus!
-你现在可以出来了 -去去，武器走
Vengeance is sweet.
真是甜蜜的复仇
How I hoped I'd be the one to catch you.
我多麻希望能欧亲手抓到你
Severus--
石内卜
I told Dumbledore you were helping a friend into the castle. Here’s the proof.
我告诉好不利多，你接应自己的 好朋友进入城堡，现在人丹俱获了
Brilliant, Snape.
太好了 ，石内上
You've put your keen mind to the task and come to the wrong conclusion.
你又再用你那难疙又敏感的内在 然后做出错误的结论
If you'll excuse us, Remus and I have business...
如果你不在意的话 我跟路平还有事情
-...to attend to. -Give me a reason. I beg you!
-要钼理 -不要让我找到藉口航了你
-Don't be a fool. -He can't help it. It’s habit.
-石内卜，不要做夯事 -他是笨蛋，专做蠢事
-Be quiet. -Be quiet yourself!
-闭跑! -你自己先装嘴 !
You two, quarrelling like an old married couple.
看看你们，就像老夫老妻在同踢
Run along and play with your chemistry set!
你干嘛不滚回去调配你的魔药
I could do it, you know.
我现在就可以角了你
But why deny the dementors? They're so longing to see you.
可是我不想浪费催狂魔 他是多广想…找到你
Do I detect a flicker of fear? Oh, yes.
你是不是怕得发持了?
A Dementor’s Kiss. One can only imagine what that must be like.
催狂魔之吻，没有人能活著述说 那是多广丽怖的经压
It's said to be nearly unbearable to witness, but I'll do my best.
区说光是在劣晃看都会让人受不了 不过我会忍耐!
Severus, please.
石内卜，不要人这样
After you.
你先请
-Harry! What did you just do? -You attacked a teacher!
-哈利，你加蜀在做什么 ? -你攻击学校老师 !
-Tell me about Peter. -He was at school with us.
-告诉我彼得佩迪备的事 -他跟我们一起上学 !
We thought he was our friend!
我们都把他当成是朋友
-No. Pettigrew’s dead. You killed him! -No, he didn’t.
不对，佩迪重已经死了 是你角死他的
I thought so too, until you mentioned Pettigrew on the map!
我本来也是这广想的 直到你在地图看到佩迪甸的名字
-The map was lying, then. -The map never lies!
-地图在说议 -地图从来不说议!
Pettigrew's alive! And he’s right there!
佩迪和鲁还活著，而且他就在那里 !
-Me?! He’s mental! -Not you! Your rat!
-我? 他根本是疯了，我… -不是你，是你的老鼠 !
-Scabbers has been in my family for-- -Twelve years?
-斑斑当我们家的宕物已经有… -十二年了!
Curiously long life for a common garden rat!
一般的雪物鼠怎入可能活这广久
-He’s missing a toe, isn't he? -So what?
-他有一个趾头不见了，对不对 ? -那又怎样 ! !
-All they could find of Pettigrew was his-- -Finger!
-他们只找到彼得佩迪重的… -手指 !
Dirty coward cut it off so everyone would think he was dead!
那个惨夫砍掉自己的指头 让大家以为他死了
-And then he transformed into a rat! -Show me.
-然后再把自己变成一焦老鼠 -证明给我看 !
-Give it to him, Ron. -What are you trying to do to him?
-把斑斑交给他 -你们打算怎庆对付他? !
Scabbers!
斑斑
Leave him alone! Get off him! What are you doing?
快点放了他 你们在做什么，住手!
Remus?
路平
Sirius.
天狼星
My old friends!
我的老朋友
Harry! Look at you. You look so much like your father.
哈利…你看看你 你长得好像你爸爸
-James. We were the best of friends-- -How dare you speak to Harry!
-好像麻姆，我们是好朋友 -你没有资格跟哈利说话
How dare you talk about James in front of him!
你竟然有脆子在他面前提起麻姆
-You sold James and Lily to Voldemort! -1 didn’t mean to!
-你把磨姆跟莉莉出责给佛地魔 -我不是故襄的
The Dark Lord. You have no idea the weapons he possesses!
你不知道黑魔王拿什么来对付我
Ask yourself, Sirius! What would you have done?
你，天狼星? 换成你会怎庆做
-What would you have done? -Died, rather than betray my friends!
-你碰上了会怎订做 -我宁愿死 ! 宁愿死也不会背叛朋友
James wouldn't have wanted me killed!
詹姆不会希望我被儿掉的
Your dad would have spared me! He would have shown me mercy!
你爸爸会原该我的 他会情帆我
Should have realized if Voldemort didn’t kill you, we would. Together!
彼得你必须了解，如果佛地魔 没有儿了你，那我们也会联手级了你
No!
不行
-Harry, this man-- - know what he is.
-哈利，这个人他… -我知道他做了什和记
But we'll take him to the castle.
可是我们要先带他去城堡
-Bless you, boy. Bless you! -Get off!
-上帝保估你，上帝保佑 -滚开
l said we'd take you to the castle.
我们现在带你去城堡
After that, the dementors can have you.
然和后，让催狂魔处置你
Sorry about the bite. l reckon that twinges a bit.
对不起，风刚咬了你 我知道会有点痛
A bit? A bit? You almost tore my leg off!
有一点痛?何止痛啊? 你刚刚差点把我的腿咬断了
I was going for the rat.
我是要追老鼠
Normally, I have a very sweet disposition as a dog.
通常我演成狗以后都非常温副
More than once, James suggested that I make the change permanent.
事实上，磨姆不只一次建议我 乾脆永下变成狗算了
The tail 1 could live with. But the fleas, they’re murder.
我是可以忍受我长尾巴 不过跳最…真是受不了
Okay.
好了
-You better go. -No. Don't worry, okay?
-你应该殖去 -不用，不会有事的
It’s fine. I'll stay.
我在这陪你
You go, I'll stay.
这里有我，去吧
-You okay? -I’m fine. Go.
-你可以吗? -没问题，快去
-That looks really painful. -So painful.
-这一定很痛 -痛死了
They might chop it.
说不定会被截肢
I'm sure Madam Pomfrey will fix it in a heartbeat.
麻秽夫人很快就会治好的
It’s too late. It’s ruined. It'll have to be chopped off.
来不及了“，腿已经订了 我一定会被截肢
It’s beautiful, isn’t it?
那里很美对不对 ?
I'll never forget the first time I walked through those doors.
我永下不会忘记第一次 走进学校的感觉
It'll be nice to do it again as a free man.
以自由之身再度走进去 感觉一定很好
That was a noble thing you did back there.
你罗列的行为真的很高沿
He doesn't deserve it.
他不值得我们动手
I didn’t think my dad would have wanted his best friends...
我只是想我爸一定不希望 他的雨个好朋友
...to become killers.
变成钨手
Besides, dead, the truth dies with him.
而且，他死了真相就优法大和白
Alive, you're free.
他活著，你才能自由
Turn me into a flobberworm. Anything but the dementors!
把我演成晤蛤或者其他什么都好 只要不是催狂魔 !
Ron! Haven't I been a good pet? You won't let them give me...
上轧，我一直都是你的好朋友 好雪物?
...to the dementors, will you? l was your rat!
你不会让他们把我交给催狂魔吧
-Sweet, clever girl! Surely you won't-- -Get away from her!
漂亮的女孩，隐明的女孩 你一定不会让他们…
I don't know if you know, Harry...
有件事我想你不知道
...but when you were born, James and Lily made me your godfather.
你出生的时候 磨姆跟痢莉让我当你的教父
I know.
我知道
I can understand if you choose to stay with your aunt and uncle...
如果你想跟你姨丈他们一起住 我可以理解
...but if you ever wanted a different home....
但如果你想有个新家，你可以…
What? Come and live with you?
什么 ? 你要我跟你住?
It’s just a thought. I can understand if you don’t want to.
其实这只是个想法 如果你不要的话那就算了
Harry!
哈利!
Remus, my old friend. Have you taken your potion tonight?
路平，我的好朋友 你今天晚上没有吃药吗?
You know the man you truly are, Remus! This heart is where you truly live! Here!
不要忘了你是个男子汉，内在的你 才是真正的你，要记住你的心
This flesh is only flesh!
外表只是假象
Harry!
哈利!
Remus! Remus!
路平 !
Run! Run!
快跑，快跑
-Come on. -Wait. Wait.
-走了 -等一下
Hermione! Bad idea. Bad idea.
-妙时 -不要啊…不要啊…
Professor?
教授?
Professor Lupin?
路平教授?
Nice doggy. Nice doggy!
乎狗狗，狗狗矢
There you are, Potter!
波特，你在这壬
Sirius!
天狼星
Come back here, Potter!
给我回来
No. Sirius!
不要，天狼星
Expecto Patronum!
疾疾，访法现身
Harry?
哈利?
l saw my dad.
我看到我爸了
What?
什么?
He sent the dementors away.
他把俊狂魔超走了
l saw him across the lake.
他在湖的另一遗
Harry, they’ve captured Sirius.
他们把天狼星抓走了
Any minute the dementors are gonna perform the Kiss.
催狂魔要去对他执行催狂魔之吻
-They’re gonna kill him? -No. It’s worse.
-称是说他们要儿了他? -不，更莉薰
They're going to suck out his soul.
他们打算吸出他的赴魂
Headmaster, stop them.
校长，你一定要阻止他们
-They’ve got the wrong man. -It’s true. Sirius is innocent.
-他们抓错人了 -没有错，天狼星是无齐的
-It'’s Scabbers who did it. -Scabbers?
-真正的多手是斑斑 -斑斑?
He’s my rat, sir.
怨是我的老鼠
He’s not really a rat. He was a rat. He was my brother Percy’s rat.
怨不是真的老鼠 怨以前是我哥哥派西的老鼠
-But then they gave him an owl-- -The point is, we know the truth.
-可是他有了猎头魔… -重时是，我们知道真相
-Please believe us. -l do, Miss Granger.
-请相信我们 -我相信你们
But the word of three 13-year-old wizards will convince few others.
可是很焉憾，世上没有人会相信 三个十三藏巫师所说的话
A child’s voice, however honest and true...
小孩所说的话就算是事实…
...is meaningless to those who have forgotten how to listen.
也扰足玛重 尤其是对那些不善聆匠的人
Mysterious thing, time.
神秘的时间啊
Powerful...
力量强大
.and when meddled with, dangerous.
尤其当一个人插手危险事物之时
Sirius Black is in the topmost cell of the Dark Tower.
天狼星被关在黑暗之塔 最高的牢房里
You know the laws, Miss Granger.
你是知道规则的，格荫像小姐
You must not be seen.
不能被人看到
And you would do well, I feel, to return before this last chime.
而我觉得你会成功 绝对能在最后一声钾结前超回来
If not, the consequences are too ghastly to discuss.
如果失败的话，结果和将十分枣怖
If you succeed tonight...
但是，如果人成功了
..-more than one innocent life may be spared.
就可以抒救丁休扰齐的性命
Three turns should do it, I think.
我想谭该翻三次就钓了
Oh, and by the way.
吗，对了
When in doubt, I find retracing my steps to be a wise place to begin.
找不到方向时 我会循著自己的脚步从头再一次
Good luck.
祝你好运
What the bloody hell was that all about?
校长他出刚到底在说些什么啊
Sorry, Ron, but seeing as you can't walk....
对不起，策思，你没办法走路
What just happened?
发生什么事了?
-Where’s Ron? -7:30.
-莹恩人呢? -现在七是半
Where were we at 7:30?
我们七点半的时候在哪里?
I don’t know. Going to Hagrid's?
我不知道，大概是海格那里吧
Come on. And we can't be seen.
快走，我们不能被别人看到
Hermione!
妙恩
Hermione! Hermione, wait.
妙对…妙采，等竺
Hermione, will you please tell me what it is we're doing?
-称可不可以告诉我怎么回事 -来参秽处决的吗?
That's us.
那是我们惠
Hermione, no! He’s not worth it.
妙采，不要 他不值得你动手
This is not normal.
这感觉好奇怪唱
This is a Time-Turner, Harry.
这叫做时光器，哈利
McGonagall gave it to me first term.
是天学的时候，堆教授给我的
This is how I've been getting to my lessons all year.
这就是为什么我能同时上两堂课
-You mean we've gone back in time? -Yes.
-称是说我们回到过去了 -对
Dumbledore obviously wanted us to return to this moment.
如不利多似乎是刻意让我们… 可到这个时间
Clearly, something happened he wants us to change.
他一定是要我们来改伙某件事情
Good punch.
打得好
Thanks.
谢了
Malfoy’s coming.
马份要过来了
-Run. -Not a word to anyone, understood?
-等等我 -谁都不准说出去
I'm gonna get that jumped-up mudblood! Mark my words.
我一定让那麻种好看，给我记住
-That felt good. -Not good, brilliant.
-感觉真好 -不是好，是岂采了
Come on. We should be at Hagrid’s.
快点，我们应该去海格那了
Look. Buckbeak’s still alive.
你看，锅跑还活著耶
Remember what Dumbledore said?
你逮记得如不利多说的吗?
If we succeed, more than one innocent life could be spared.
他说如果成功了 就可以抒救丁休扰齐的性命
Let's go.
我们走吧
Here they come. I'd better hurry.
他们来了 我们要快一点
Fudge has to see Buckbeak before we steal him.
我们要先让夫子看到饥距
Otherwise, he'll think Hagrid set him free.
不然的话他会以为是海格放走的
Scabbers, you're alive!
斑斑，你还活著
-Keep a closer eye on your pet. -That’s Pettigrew.
-你要好好盯住… -那是彼得佩迪入
-Harry, you can’t. -He betrayed my parents.
-哈利，不可以过去 -背叛我父母的人就在那里
-You don't expect me to sit here. -Yes, and you must!
-虹不会要我坐视不管吧 -没错，你非这样不可
Harry, you're in Hagrid’s hut now.
哈利，你现在人是在海格的屋里
If you go bursting in, you'll think you've gone mad.
如果你就这样阅进去 人们会觉得你瘦掉了
Awful things happen to wizards who meddle with time.
摄乱时间的巫师 是很容易发生可怕的事
We can't be seen.
我们绝对不能被人家看到
Fudge is coming.
夫子来了
And we aren't leaving?
我们不肯走?
Why aren't we leaving?
为什么我们不走?
Are you mad?
你疯啦
That hurt.
那很痛陡
Sorry.
对不起
We're coming out the back door. Go!
我们要从和后门出来了，快
Is that really what my hair looks like from the back?
我的头桶从和后面看是这样子吗?
What?
怎庆了?
I thought I just saw....
我蜀蜀好像看到…
-Never mind. -Let’s go.
-没什么 -我们走吧,
Okay, go, Harry. Go!
走，哈利，走吧
Get away. Get off.
滚并，冈一站去
Minister, I really think I should sign as well.
部长，我觉得我也应该签名
Yes, very well. Perhaps it would be....
你能一起签名作证是再好不过了
Okay, Buckbeak. Come quickly. Come with us now. Come on.
好了，和锅路，快点来 跟我们一起走
Keep trying. Come on. Quickly.
快拉，继续拉，快点
Buckbeak. Okay? Quickly. Hurry up. Okay?
高嘴，贡话，快点好吗?9
-Your name only. -It’s such a very long name....
-签这休线上，签名字就行了 -我的名字殷长啊
Hurry up now, Buckbeak, okay?
快点，锅跑，好吗?
Come on. Come on, Buckbeak.
高嘴，快点来
Come and get the nice dead ferret.
有好吃的才貂肉虽
-Come on. It's here. Come on, Beaky. -Here we are, minister. Follow me.
-快点来，人这里，这壬 -好了，部长，请跟我来
-Now, look there. -Where?
-看到那晃了没有? -哪下 ?
-Look beyond the rocks. -What am ! supposed to see?
-就在岩石过去 -你要我看什么?
Professor Dippet had that ling planted when he was headmaster.
迪平教授扩任校长的时候 在那冰种了石南
-Oh, yes. Indeed, indeed. -And all the strawberries.
-对…没错，没错 -还有那些草花
-Come on, Buckbeak. Come on. -l see no strawberries.
-快点过来，饥踢 -我没看到草莓啊?
-Over there. -Where?
就在那逮
-This way.
-在那录 -往这壬
-Let’s get this over, please. -All right.
-好了“，我们来执行吧 -好吧
But where is it?
怨跑到哪儿去了?
I saw the beast, just now.
我刚刚还看到忽
-Not a moment ago! -How extraordinary.
-刚刚逮在这里的 -真是太奇怪了
Buckbeak.
高嘴 ?
Come now, Dumbledore. Someone's obviously released him.
拜旗，避不利多 一定是有人把怨放走了
-Hagrid? -Buckbeak.
海格 ?
I don’t think the minister’s suggesting you had anything to do with this.
我想部长益不认为 你跟这件事情有关俐
How could you? You've been with us all the time.
怎么可能是你? 你一直跟我们在一起
-Right. -Well, well...
-是啊 -好啦，好啦
We must search the grounds.
我们一定要搜遍这一带
Well, search the skies, if you must, minister.
我建议你应该搜可天空，部长
Meanwhile, I'd like a nice cup of tea or a large brandy.
现在，我想来一杯好茶 或是一大杯白苦地
Oh, executioner, your services are no longer required.
创子手 现在你不需要执行任务了
Thank you.
谢谢
You'll find no small glasses in this house, professor.
教授，我这还真是没有小杯子
-Come on. -This way.
-来吧 -这下
This way, now.
跟我来
-Now what? -We save Sirius.
-接下来呢? -我们要救天狼星
-How? -No idea.
一怎订救? -不知道
-Look. It’s Lupin. -immobulus!
-你看，是路平教授 -静止 !
And Snape’s coming.
石内下来了
And now we wait.
我们只能等了
-At least someone's enjoying himself. -Yeah.
-至少有人现在心情不错 -是的
-Hermione? -Yeah?
-妙朴了? -什么事?
Before, down by the lake, when I was with Sirius...
天刚…我跟天狼星在湖站的时候
...1 did see someone.
我真的看到有人
That someone made the dementors go away.
那个人把催狂魔通通超走了
With a Patronus.
那是用访法加
I heard Snape telling Dumbledore.
我区到石内下告诉好不利多
According to him...
他的说法是…
...only a really powerful wizard could have conjured it.
只有法力很强的巫师才能金做到
It was my dad.
那是我爸
My dad conjured the Patronus.
召唤访法响的人是我爸爸
-Harry, but your dad’s-- -Dead. I know.
-可是哈利，你和爸已经… -死了，我知道
I'm just telling you what I saw.
我只是告诉你我看到了什和记
Here we come.
我们出来了
You see Sirius talking to me there?
看到我跟天狼星在那下说话吗?
-He’s asking me to come live with him. -That’s great.
-他阅我要不要跟他一起住 -很好啊
When we free him, I'll never have to go back to the Dursleys’.
等他自由以后，我就… 再也不用回德思礼家了
It'll just be me and him.
我们可以相依为命
We could live in the country...
我们可以住在乡下
...-someplace you can see the sky.
一个看得到天空的地方
He'll like that after all those years in Azkaban.
他被并了那记多年 一定很守往那里
Harry!
哈利!
Run!
快跑 !
Let's go.
我们走吧
-What are you doing? -Saving your life.
丈在堤嘛? -我在救你啊
Thanks.
谢了
-Great. Now he’s coming for us. -Yeah, I didn't think about that. Run!
-这下好了，他来找我们了 -没错，我没想到这一点，快跑
That was so scary.
到刚好可怕
Poor Professor Lupin’s having a really tough night.
可屋的路平教授今晚很不好过
Sirius. Come on!
天狼星，快走
-This is horrible. -Don't worry.
-真是太恐怖了 -别担心
My dad will come. He’ll conjure the Patronus.
我爸爸会出现，他会召唤访法加
Any minute now.
他马上就会出现
Right there. You'll see.
就在那稳，会看到的
Harry, listen to me. No one’s coming.
哈利，匠我说，没有人会出现的
Don't worry, he will. He will come.
别担心，他会来的，他一定会来
-Sirius. -You're dying...
你快死了…
...both of you.
天狼星也是
Harry!
哈利!
Expecto Patronum!
疾疾，访法现身
You were right, Hermione.
你说得没错，妙忆
It wasn't my dad I saw earlier. It was me!
我看到的不是我爸爸，而是我
I saw myself conjuring the Patronus before.
我是看到我自己召唤出护法加
I knew I could do it this time because...
我知道我做得到了“，因为…
... well, [ had already done it.
我自己亲眼看到了
-Does that make sense? -No.
-这是不是很奇怪 ? -没错
But I don’t like flying...!
可是我不喜欢悉行
Bombarda!
听听碰
I'll be forever grateful for this...
我会永速感谢你们…
...to both of you.
救了我一命
-l want to go with you. -One day, perhaps.
-我要跟你一起走 -总有一天会的
For some time, my life will be too unpredictable.
我的人生实在是太过千变菌化
And besides...
而且……
-...you're meant to be here. -But you're innocent.
-你应该留在这里 -可是你是无享的
And you know it.
你知道我是无齐的
And for now, that will do.
我想这榜已经金了
l expect you're tired of hearing this...
这名话你大概隐腻了
...but you look so like your father.
不过你跟你爸爸真的很像
Except your eyes.
除了限且以外
-You have-- -My mother’s eyes.
-你的… -限像妈妈
It’s cruel that I spent so much time with James and Lily, and you so little.
造化弄人，我跟你父母朝夕相处 跟你相处的时间征这麻短
But know this:
你要记住
The ones that love us never really leave us.
所有真心党我们的人 都会在我们的身逮
And you can always find them...
他们永焉会陪伴著你
..in here.
在你心里
You really are the brightest witch of your age.
你真的是同年龄里最陷明的女巫
We have to go.
我们必须走了
-Well? -He’s free. We did it.
-什么事? -他自由了“，我们做到了
Did what?
做了什么 ?
Good night.
晚安吐
How did you get there?
你们怎订冒出来的?
l was talking to you there. And now you're there.
我们刚刚才在这下讲话 现在人估在那逮
-What’s he talking about, Harry? -I don’t know.
-他在说什么啊，哈利? -我也不知道
Honestly, Ron. How can somebody be in two places at once?
说真的，一个人怎么可能 同时出现在雨个地方
Hello, Harry.
你好，哈利
I saw you coming.
我看到你走过来了
I've looked worse, believe me.
我只是看起来不太好而已
-You've been sacked. -No.
-你被开除了? -不对
No. I resigned, actually.
不，我是主动辞职的
Resigned? Why?
人辞职? 为什么?
Well, it seems that somebody let slip the nature of my condition.
因为好像有人把我的状况说出去
This time tomorrow, the owls will start arriving and parents will not want...
明天这时候，就会有很多猎头麻 送家长的抗议信来
..-well, someone like me teaching their children.
说不要像我这样的人 教汐他们的孩子
-But Dumbledore-- -He has already...
-可是，几不利多… -好不利多
...tisked enough on my behalf.
其实已经为我做金多了
Besides, people like me are....
更何况，像我这样的人…
Well, let's just say that I'm used to it by now.
老实说，我也已经习惯了
Why do you look so miserable, Harry?
哈利，你心情看起来好差
None of it made any difference.
一切都没有改变
-Pettigrew escaped. -Didn’t make any difference?
-佩迪重逃走了 -什么叫一切都没有改变?
It made all the difference in the world. You uncovered the truth.
你完全改党了一切 你揭露出事实真相
If l am proud of anything...
要说我有什么能引以为傲的
. it is of how much you have learned this year.
就是你这一年学到了很多
Now, since I am no longer your teacher...
既然我已经不再是你老师了
.. 1 feel no guilt whatsoever about giving this back to you.
把这个东西还给你 我也就不会有罪恶感了
So now I'll say goodbye, Harry.
现在我们该说再见了“，哈利
I feel sure we'll meet again sometime.
我有预感我们一定会再见面
Until then...
一直到…
... mischief managed.
显作完成
Stand back, I said! Or I'll take it upstairs if you don't settle.
快点后退啦 你们不冬一点，我就把它拿回去
Harry.
哈利
Wherever did you get it?
你怎订会有人这个?
Can I have a go, Harry? After you, of course.
可以让我骑一下吗? 当然你先骑了
-What are you talking about? -Quiet.
-你们在说什么? -大家安静
Let the man through. I didn’t mean to open it, Harry.
让主角过来 我不是故意要打并的，哈利
It was badly wrapped. They made me do it.
可是这个包装得不太好 他们融我打开的
Did not.
才没有呢
-It’s a Firebolt. -It’s the fastest broom in the world.
-火闵电台 -这是最快的飞天抬斋
For me?
给我的吗?
-But who sent it? -No one knows.
-是座寄来的? -没有人知道
This came with it.
这是附在包庄上的
-Go on, Harry! -Yeah, let's see.
-快点 ! 哈利 -双啊，让我们瞧鸭
How fast is it, Harry?
哈利，它能惧多快?
Lumos.
路摸思
f solemnly swear that [am up to no good.
我郊重发将，我绝对不怀好意
Mischief managed.
显作完成
Nox.
啊刻斯
[ENGLISH]
[MANDARIN - R3]